<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[P's Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Personal blog by Princiya Sequeira]]></description><link>http://princiya.com/blog</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 20:27:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Introduction to contract tests]]></title><description><![CDATA[An introduction to contract tests and comparison with integration tests]]></description><link>http://princiya.com/blog/contract-tests-introduction/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://princiya.com/blog/contract-tests-introduction/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;context&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#context&quot; aria-hidden class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It became evident to the Frontend team that &lt;a href=&quot;https://swagger.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Swagger&lt;/a&gt; documentation alone will not suffice due to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Properties from the api response get added / removed / updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no way to inform the stakeholders (FE in our case) about the above change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to these reasons, we want to test an integration point by checking each application (BE or FE) in isolation to ensure the messages it sends or receives conform to a shared understanding that is documented in a “contract”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In simple terms, we want to test the integration point with our BE API client to ensure it sends HTTP response or receives HTTP requests from our web or mobile front-end conforms to a shared understanding that is documented in a “contract”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;terminology&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#terminology&quot; aria-hidden class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Terminology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consumer&lt;/strong&gt; —&gt; The one who consumes the information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provider&lt;/strong&gt; —&gt; The one who provids the information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to note that, contract tests enable testing of applications from either ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; The backend can be contract tested with a mock frontend and viceversa. Both the backend and frontend can interchange and act as the consumer or the provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contract is generated during the execution of the automated tests. The &lt;strong&gt;consumer generates contract files&lt;/strong&gt; during the execution of its isolated tests. The &lt;strong&gt;provider generates verification results&lt;/strong&gt; during the execution of its isolated tests. These artifacts need to be shared between projects and people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;decision&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#decision&quot; aria-hidden class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Decision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use &lt;a href=&quot;https://pact.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Pact&lt;/a&gt; as the contract test framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;consequences&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#consequences&quot; aria-hidden class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Consequences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable FE teams to (sometimes) work ahead while the BE API is still being developed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The consumer and provider are both under active development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contract tests execute faster than the integration tests and will tell which versions of our applications can be deployed safely together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can find out before we deploy whether or not our applications will work together, i.e. this version of FE against a given version of BE; and there is no need to wait for slow e2e tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;contract-vs-integration-tests&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#contract-vs-integration-tests&quot; aria-hidden class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Contract vs Integration tests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first heard the term contract testing only last month mainly when we were trying to figure out how to have better API tests and that the BE changes become more visible to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integration tests or end to end tests (offcourse these two are not same) require the application to be setup, or run beforehand to enable the tests themselves to run. This is the biggest key difference between integration and contract tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:
Imagine you are planning to buy / rent a house. First you will see the house itself. If it interests you then you will sign the contract. The contract will then detail what is agreed between you and the other person selling / renting the place. This contract will then serve as the basis. If anything needs to change, then you need to update the contract itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace the house with the application. You are the consumer, the owner of the house is the provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you will see the house itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will build the application, run unit tests, and test the application locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it interests you then you will sign the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contract tests are run with what is agreed between the consumer and the provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You didn’t have to move into the house to sign the contract. But the contract was the first agreement before moving into the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the same with deploying the application itself to production or staging environment. The consumer contract tests can be tested against a mock provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas for the integration tests to be run, the application first needs to be deployed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know what your thoughts are.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top=55px; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(This is an article posted to my blog at overreacted.io. You can read it online by &lt;a href=&quot;http://princiya.com/blog/contract-tests-introduction/&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;
              </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What would I advice my younger self]]></title><description><![CDATA[Lessons from my younger self]]></description><link>http://princiya.com/blog/lessons-from-my-younger-self/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://princiya.com/blog/lessons-from-my-younger-self/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Many a times I come across Twitter posts which ask -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would you advice your younger self?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was very good at academics and when I enrolled into the university for my under graduate studies I knew that I would definitely crack the campus recruitment and would be placed in a company with handsome salary. But &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;11 years ago&lt;/code&gt;, in 2009, there was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/2009/01/14/global-recession-2009-oped-cx_nr_0115roubini.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;global recession&lt;/a&gt; and things didn’t go as planned with me in securing a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still remember that day; the first company which came for campus placement was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tcs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;TCS&lt;/a&gt;. I was shocked to find out that I hadn’t cleared the aptitude test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first failure in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I used to actively participate in extra curriculars since my school days, I did lose quite a few competitions but that was all in a sportive mood and my life wasn’t hanging around those failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cried profusely that day after the first failed campus placement results. I was hopeful that I would make it to the next company but this kept happening couple more times and I had no clue about what was going wrong. I gave up after a few attempts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt like I needed a break after studying all those years so hard and not being able to find my dream job. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That year, I took up a teaching job and for the next two years I worked as a Lecturer in Computer Science at an engineering college. I was happy, some of my colleagues were my best friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside teaching I took up some freelance web development work and I realised that I was ready for newer challenges. In 2011, I quit the teaching job and joined as a full time Software Engineer and rest is &lt;a href=&quot;../two-years-into-leadership&quot;&gt;history&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have worked hard all through these years and if there’s any advice I could give my younger self then that is -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything happens for good&lt;/strong&gt;. You will never realise at that point of time, so instead of being sad when things don’t turn your way try to find the positive side of things and keep working hard. There comes a time when all the hard work will be worth it and you will realise for yourself that &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;everything does happen for good&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following quote from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A._P._J._Abdul_Kalam&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Dr. Abdul Kalam&lt;/a&gt; is my all time favorite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dream is not what you get in sleep, Dream is what makes you lose your sleep!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top=55px; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(This is an article posted to my blog at overreacted.io. You can read it online by &lt;a href=&quot;http://princiya.com/blog/lessons-from-my-younger-self/&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;
              </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Career advice]]></title><description><![CDATA[Lessons from my younger self]]></description><link>http://princiya.com/blog/career-advice/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://princiya.com/blog/career-advice/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Many a times I come across Twitter posts which ask -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would you advice your younger self?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;../okr&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I described how we created OKRs at Curalie. Apart from filling the below table -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Good&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bad&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Like&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;xx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;xx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dislike&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;xx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;xx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also asked my colleagues to think about the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short term goal (6 months from now)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medium term goal (1 year from now)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long term goal (far vision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was quite interesting to listen to the answers and this made me wonder how my younger self would have answered to these same questions. In one of my earlier &lt;a href=&quot;../lessons-from-my-younger-self&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; I spoke about how things were for me a decade ago!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I started working full time as a Software Engineer, during the first year I did UI development only. Having freshly graduated from college, jQuery was new to me and we were using it back then. There were few things about jQuery which I could not understand well, it was also because I never really understood JavaScript. At my second job at Aiaioo Labs, is when I met this awesome mentor and I learned from him how to learn coding the right way. Critical thinking is crucial for programmers and he thought me how to think about every line of code written. Code should not be written for the sake of writing, but we need to understand what we expect to achieve and what we want the machines to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example: I was blindly using &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;position: absolute vs relative&lt;/code&gt; and it took some time to really get a hang of asking why was i using &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;absolute vs relative&lt;/code&gt; positioning, and once I started doing this it became more frequent and more natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had to opportunity to do full-stack, understand about BE systems, dev ops, databases, UI design etc. If I can recollect, it is the learning environment which I had which led me learn and grow. Sometimes I had to do photoshop, sometimes Java, or sometimes think about why our nodes were down or running slowly. I was also taking basic lessons on machine learning. I remember signing up &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; number of times to this course on Coursera, but never completed it. I was working at a startup, and lot of people including my parents were asking me to leave this company and join a bigger firm. But I stuck to it mainly because I realised how much I had to learn. As they say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No risk, no story!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After about ~5 years, I decided I wanted to dig deeper into the frontend universe. The role of full-stack didn’t make much sense to me because I started to think that one can never get really good at full-stack given the growing no. of technologies, languages and frameworks. That’s when I landed a job in Berlin and started working as a full-time frontend engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, when I lead other engineers, I wonder and realised had I not had the opportunity to do full-stack, it would have not been possible for me to understand cross-domain dependencies or quickly build prototypes to evaluate a feature or a project. The advice from my previous post is still relevant -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything happens for good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, during these years I have attended numerous technical interviews, failed at tons and have answered this golden question or taught to myself about what I want to be in the long run. Sometimes I have blindly blabbered that I wanted to be the CTO but not knowing or not having a plan about how to get there. My mentor, during my second job did also a good job in making me realise what I was lacking or what I had to achieve / master to reach the end goal. He always saw me as a good programmer, but sometimes I was lazy and was not pushing myself beyond my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So coming back to the point about listening to my directs tell me what their short / long term goals were, and thinking what I would have answered, it made me realise that my answers wouldn’t or have not been different. The short term goal was always to get good at one particular thing, for example &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;writing tests&lt;/code&gt;. The long term goal was &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;getting good at everything&lt;/code&gt;. Now comes the tricky part about one cannot be good at everything. One can do everything but can never be good at everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as a leader, I suggest people to chase their dreams. Create a learning curve of yourself, get it verified from my peers or mentors. Find yourself a mentor. Nowadays there is internet and lot of options to find a mentor. Do things out of your comfort zone, try to push yourself hard. Pick one topic where you want to get good at and draw out an effective plan or a strategy to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be afraid to ask questions and most importantly make sure it makes you happy!&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top=55px; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(This is an article posted to my blog at overreacted.io. You can read it online by &lt;a href=&quot;http://princiya.com/blog/career-advice/&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;
              </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[OKRs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Objectives and key results]]></description><link>http://princiya.com/blog/okr/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://princiya.com/blog/okr/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1 id=&quot;context&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#context&quot; aria-hidden class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For Q3, we are working on launching &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OKR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Objectives and key results (OKRs)&lt;/a&gt; for the company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here’s my &lt;a href=&quot;../two-years-into-leadership&quot;&gt;recent article&lt;/a&gt; about what I accomplished at Curalie GmbH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspired by the book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whatmatters.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Measure What Matters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/tradecraft-traction/this-chart-can-tell-you-when-its-time-to-leave-your-job-6926e0be9228&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; which describes about what you are good / bad at vs what you like / dislike, I asked my directs to fill in the following table:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Good&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bad&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Like&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;xx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;xx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dislike&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;xx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;xx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The term &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Bad&lt;/code&gt; necessarily doesn’t mean what you are bad at, but it also means what you want to improve on, sometimes you haven’t had the time to do a particular task despite you having liked it etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At first, I did this activity myself and realised how difficult it was to arrive at the columns for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;dislike &amp;#x26; bad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;dislike &amp;#x26; good&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The latter was easier than the former.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having realised this, I asked everyone to think deep and reflect on the nature of the work, learning curve, product etc. to be able to figure out the difficult parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gist of this table is to ensure that nothing is really there on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;dislike &amp;#x26; bad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; column.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If something is there then that should be the immediate action item to work on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;consequences&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#consequences&quot; aria-hidden class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Consequences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once this activity was done, the next step was to align this table with the OKRs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The alternate way to look at this table is to look at the &lt;strong&gt;Good&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Bad&lt;/strong&gt; columns from a company’s perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example, if you mentioned something in the &lt;strong&gt;Bad&lt;/strong&gt; column, you could look into this as &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;if this is really bad for the company&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;Good&lt;/strong&gt; for you, might be &lt;strong&gt;Bad&lt;/strong&gt; for the company or vice versa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on this, it gets quite easy to create objectives and key results for a quarter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
                &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top=55px; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(This is an article posted to my blog at overreacted.io. You can read it online by &lt;a href=&quot;http://princiya.com/blog/okr/&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;
              </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dart]]></title><description><![CDATA[So I tried Dart today for the first time]]></description><link>http://princiya.com/blog/dart/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://princiya.com/blog/dart/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1 id=&quot;dart&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dart&quot; aria-hidden class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dart&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I tried &lt;a href=&quot;https://flutter.dev&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Flutter&lt;/a&gt; for the first time. Flutter is Google’s UI toolkit for building beautiful, natively compiled applications for mobile, web, and desktop from a single codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;https://dart.dev&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Dart&lt;/a&gt; is the programming language used to code Flutter apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, I have tried hybrid mobile app frameworks, but they all use WebView under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dart is quite promising, no WebView and all code written gets compiled to native platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dart is similar to React Native, but doesn’t need to use a bridge like React Native and is even faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you are looking for a single codebase, multiple platforms, Flutter is your framework of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top=55px; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(This is an article posted to my blog at overreacted.io. You can read it online by &lt;a href=&quot;http://princiya.com/blog/dart/&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;
              </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Two year work anniversary]]></title><description><![CDATA[It's official, I now have 2 years work experience as a leader]]></description><link>http://princiya.com/blog/two-years-into-leadership/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://princiya.com/blog/two-years-into-leadership/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;July 01, 2020 is my two year work anniversary with &lt;a href=&quot;https://curalie.de&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Curalie GmbH&lt;/a&gt;. It’s been great two years until now, I have enjoyed working here every single day (there have been very few blue days) and I look forward to the upcoming challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 years ago, I was looking for a job change and was very much open to take bigger responsibilities and the Open Source Manager job at Zalando happened. Prior to this, I was working as a Software Engineer at Collabary (by Zalando). Although the job was challenging, I didn’t qualify there to a higher pay grade. And my previous manager said I was going through the Dunning Kruger effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was determined to get a better job, title and offcourse higher pay. 2 years now and I could not have been happier from where I am currently.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top=55px; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(This is an article posted to my blog at overreacted.io. You can read it online by &lt;a href=&quot;http://princiya.com/blog/two-years-into-leadership/&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;
              </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Interview advice]]></title><description><![CDATA[General interview tips]]></description><link>http://princiya.com/blog/interview-advice/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://princiya.com/blog/interview-advice/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about yourself&lt;/strong&gt; —&gt; Mention what you want them to hear or know about you; your learnings, accomplishments etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep a list of accomplishments ready&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important learnings, lessons learned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learnings relevant to tech stack, general team building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interviewer always looks for —&gt; tech competency, most importantly &lt;strong&gt;learning + team fit&lt;/strong&gt; —&gt; longer vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buzzwords —&gt; domain driven design —&gt; people will catch you on those terms —&gt; BEM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key learning is not to stress and just tell what you have learned from your work experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch out for expressions from the other person —&gt; if they compliment you on your answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s totally ok to tell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t know&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have used this but now I cannot recall and I might need to browse on the internet; plus one to ‘if I remember correctly’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep questions handy to the interviewer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also ask questions about what their accomplishments were, motivations to the other person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
                &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top=55px; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(This is an article posted to my blog at overreacted.io. You can read it online by &lt;a href=&quot;http://princiya.com/blog/interview-advice/&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;
              </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[Setting up a Gatsby Blog]]></description><link>http://princiya.com/blog/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://princiya.com/blog/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1 id=&quot;hello-world&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hello-world&quot; aria-hidden class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Hello World&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently subsribed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bloggingfordevs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Monica Lent’s&lt;/a&gt; newsletter to get better with blogging, writing content and mainly learning and getting better with SEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a first step, I am migrating away from my old &lt;a href=&quot;https://princiya777.wordpress.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wordpress blog&lt;/a&gt; to a self owned one and I choose Gatsby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, I’ve tried Jekyll and Hugo static site generators but was not happy when I had to make some small changes and the learning curve there was too high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like Gatsby, given my React experience, and I am finally happy with a static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I am, with a new digital garden of my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://princiya.com/blog/blog/hello-world/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top=55px; font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;(This is an article posted to my blog at overreacted.io. You can read it online by &lt;a href=&quot;http://princiya.com/blog/hello-world/&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;
              </content:encoded></item></channel></rss>